So now, this is my solution for this exercise
下面说说我是如何
on calculating the output of this small simple neural network.
计算这个小型简单神经网络输出的
So, remember that what we want to do is multiply our features by our weights,
我们需要将 features 与 weights 相乘
so features times weights.
即 features * weights
So these tensors, they work basically the same as NumPy arrays,
它们是张量 基本上和 NumPy 数组一样
if you've used NumPy before.
如果你之前用过 NumPy   应该就会很熟悉
So, when you multiply features times weights,
features 与 weights 相乘时
it'll just take the first element from each one, multiply them together,
两者里的第一个元素互相相乘
take the second element and multiply them together and so
然后是两者里的第二个元素互相相乘
on and give you back a new tensor,
依次进行
where there's element by element multiplication.
得出新的张量
So, from that we can do torch.sum to sum it all up into one value,
然后运行 torch.sum 得出一个和
add our bias term and then pass it through the activation function and then we get Y.
加上偏差项 传入激活函数并得出 y
So, we can also do this where we do features times weights again,
再介绍一种方法 同样是 features * weights
and this creates another tensor,
创建另一个张量
but tensors have a method.sum,
而张量有一个 .sum 方法
where you just take a tensor do.sum and then it sums up all the values in that tensor.
你可以传入张量   运行 .sum    它会对该张量里的所有值求和
So, we can either do it this way or we do torch.sum,
因此 我们可以运行 torch.sum
or we can just take this method,
或者采用此方法
this sum method of a tensor and some upper values that way.
对张量运行 .sum 并求和
Again, pass it through our our activation function.
同样 传入激活函数
So, here what we're doing, we're doing
这部分的作用是
this element wise multiplication and taking the sum in two separate operations.
用两种方式进行元素级乘法运算并求和
We're doing this multiplication and then we're doing the sum.
相乘 然后求和
But you can actually do this in the same operation using matrix multiplication.
但实际上可以使用矩阵乘法进行相同的运算
So, in general, you're going to be wanting to
大多数情况下
use matrix multiplications most of the time,
都建议使用矩阵乘法
since they're the more efficient and
因为矩阵乘法更高效
these linear algebra operations have been accelerated using modern libraries,
这些线性代数运算已经使用现代库加快了速度
such as CUDA that run on GPUs.
例如在 GPU 上运行的 CUDA
To do matrix multiplication in PyTorch with our two tensors features and weights,
要在 PyTorch 中对 features 和 weights 这两个张量进行矩阵乘法运算
we can use one of two methods.
我们可以采用两种方法
So, either torch.mm or torch.matmul.
分别是 torch.mm 和 torch.matmul
So, torch.mm, so matrix multiplication is more
对于 torch.mm  矩阵乘法更简单
simple and more strict about the tensors that you pass in.
并且对传入的张量要求更严格
So, torch.matmul, it actually supports broadcasting.
对于 torch.matmul 它实际上支持广播
So, if you put in tensors that have weird sizes,
如果你传入大小/形状很奇怪的张量
weird shapes, then you could get an output that you're not expecting.
那么你可能会获得意料之外的输出结果
So, what I tend to use torch.mm more often,
因此我更愿意使用 torch.mm
so that it does what I expect basically,
它能按照我的预期方式进行运算
and then if I get something wrong it's going throw an error instead of just
如果我操作错了 它就报错
doing it and continuing the calculations.
而不是继续运算
So, however, if we actually try to use
但是 如果我们尝试
torch.mm with features and weights, we'll get an error.
对 features 和 weights 使用 torch.mm  就会出错
So, here we see RuntimeError, size mismatch.
这里显示 RuntimeError: size mismatch
So, what this means is that we passed in our two tensors to torch.mm,
表示我们向 torch.mm 传入了两个张量
but there's a mismatch in the sizes and it can't actually do
但是大小不匹配 它不能进行矩阵乘法运算
the matrix multiplication and it lists out the sizes here.
并在这里列出了大小
So, the first tensor,
第一个张量
M1 is one by five and the second tensor is one by five also.
m1 是 [1 x 5] 第二个张量也是 [1 x 5]
So, if you remember from your linear algebra classes or if you studied it recently,
如果你还记得线性代数课程的知识
when you're doing matrix multiplication,
就会发现在进行矩阵乘法运算时
the first matrix has to have a number of
第一个矩阵的列数
columns that's equal to the number of rows in the second matrix.
必须等于第二个矩阵的行数
So, really what we need is we need our weights tensor,
因此 weights 张量
our weights matrix to be five by one instead of one by five.
必须是 [5 x 1] 而不是 [1 x 5]
To checkout the shape of tensors,
在构建神经网络时
as you're building your networks,
如果要查看张量的形状
you want to use tensor.shape.
你可以使用 tensor.shape
So, this is something you're going to be using all the time in PyTorch,
我们以后会频繁用到这个方法 不仅在 PyTorch 里
but also in TensorFlow and in other deep learning frameworks So,
在 TensorFlow 和其他深度学习框架中也不例外
most of the errors you're going to see when you're building networks and
在构建神经网络时 最常见的错误就是形状错误
just a lot of the difficulty when it comes to
所以 在设计神经网络架构时
designing the architecture of neural networks is getting
很重要的步骤就是
the shapes of your tensors to work right together.
使张量的形状保持匹配
So, what that means is that a large part of debugging,
也就是说 在调试过程中
you're actually going to be trying to look at
很大一部分工作是
the shape of your tensors as they're going through your network.
查看传入网络中的张量的形状
So, remember this, tensor.shape.
记得用 tensor.shape()
So, for reshaping tensors,
要变形张量
there are three, in general,
通常可以采用
three different options to choose from.
三种不同的方法
So, we have these methods;
也就是这三种方法
reshape, resize, and view.
Reshape() resize() 和 view()
The way these all work, in general,
原理基本相通 即
is that you take your tensor
对于 weights.reshape
weights.reshape and then pass in the new shape that you want.
传入想要的新形状
So, in this case,
在这个练习中
you want to change our weights to be a five by one matrix,
我们要将 weights 变成 5x1 的矩阵
so we'd say.reshape and then five comma one.
输入 .reshape(5, 1)
So, reshape here, what it will do is it's going to
reshape 的作用是
return a new tensor with the same data as weights.
返回一个新的张量 其中的数据和 weights 的一样
So, the same data that's sitting in memory at those addresses in memory.
即在内存地址中存储的相同数据
So, it's going to basically just create
它将创建一个新的张量
a new tensor that has the shape that you requested,
形状是你要求的形状
but the actual data in memory isn't being changed.
但内存中的实际数据没有改变
But that's only sometimes.
这种情况有时候会发生
Sometimes it does return a clone and what that means is that it actually
有时候 它会返回克隆版本
copies the data to another part of memory and then returns
也就是说 它将数据复制到内存的另一个部分
you a tensor on top of that part of the memory.
然后返回在此内存部分存储的张量
As you can imagine when it actually does that,
也就是说
when it's copying the data that's less efficient than if you had
复制数据比直接更改张量形状（不克隆数据）
just changed the shape of your tensor without cloning the data.
效率要低
To do something like that,
要这么做
we can use resize, where there's underscore at the end.
我们可以使用 resize_   末尾有个下划线
The underscore means that this method is an in-place operation.
下划线表示这个方法是原地操作
So, when it's in-place,
原地操作是指
that basically means that you're just not touching the data
根本不更改数据
at all and all you're doing is changing
只是更改
the tensor that's sitting on top of that addressed data in memory.
位于该内存地址中的数据对应的张量
The problem with the resize method is that if you request
resize_ 方法的问题在于
a shape that has more or less elements than the original tensor,
如果请求的形状比原始张量的元素多或少
then you can actually cut off,
你可能会丢失数据
you can actually lose some of the data that you had or you can
或者使用未初始化的内存
create this spurious data from uninitialized memory.
创建虚假的数据
So instead, what you typically want is
通常这时候
that you want a method that's going to return an error
如果有一个方法
if you changed the shape from
能在你把原始数量的元素更改为不同数量的元素的时候
the original number of elements to a different number of elements.
进行报错 是不是很好
So, we can actually do that with.view.
我们其实有这么个方法 就是 .view
So.view is the one that I use the most,
.view 是我频繁使用的一个方法
and basically what it does it just returns a new tensor
它会返回一个新张量
with the same data in memory as weights.
包含的数据和 weights 在内存中的一样
This is just all the time, 100 percent of the time,
对的
all it's going to do is return a new tensor without
它只是返回一个新的张量
messing with any of the data in memory.
不会更改内存中的任何数据
If you tried to get a new size,
如果你想获取新的尺寸
a new shape for your tensor with a different number of elements,
使张量具有新的形状和不同数量的元素
it'll return an error.
就会报错
So, you are basically using.view,
使用 .view 可以确保
you're ensuring that you will always get
在更改 weights 的形状时
the same number of elements when you change the shape of your weights.
始终获得相同数量的元素
So, this is why I typically use when I'm reshaping tensors.
这就是我在变形张量时 会用到这个方法的原因
So, with all that out of the way,
好了 总结下
if you want to reshape weights to have five rows and one column,
如果你要将 weights 变形为 5 行和 1 列
then you can use something like weights.view (5, 1), right.
可以输入 weights.view(5, 1)
So, now, that you have seen how you can change
现在 你已经知道如何改变张量的形状
the shape of a tensor and also do matrix multiplication,
以及如何进行矩阵乘法运算
so this time I want you to calculate the output of
我希望你能使用矩阵乘法
this little neural network using matrix multiplication.
计算这个小型神经网络的输出